# **RIDHO FEBRIANSA**

# Frontend Engineer

### ☑ ridho@fbrns.co ☑ https://fbrns.co ♀ Palmerah, West Jakarta

With 3 years of experience delivering commercial projects professionally, using React and Vue as the frameworks to build client facing interface. Building various apps, from canva-like web application, to a enterprise web application to manage all source of data in an omnichannel project. Active contributor and volunteer in local tech community.

# **Experience**

## Product Manager | Zero One Group - Indonesia

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

- Zero One Group (ZOG) provides bespoke software development with worldwide clients and the ability to deliver outstanding results through comprehending both business and technical requirements.
- Manage a team of 5 engineers in a 6 months project to solve infrastructure scaling and deployment issues
- Able to run an autoscaling on a Magento framework and reduce deployment time up to 10 minutes

### Product Engineer | Zero One Group - Indonesia

Mar 2022 - Dec 2022

- Collaborate with 7+ other engineers to build an omnichannel system with an enterprise client using React.js, held an
  offline training and knowledge sharing session with client engineering team and following Test Driven Development
  method
- Collaborate with 12+ other engineers to build an inventory and warehousing system for fish using React.js and following Test Driven Development method
- Take a part in an internal sharing session to share a perspective about how to be an engineer with a good domain knowledge and a good product ownership

### Junior Developer | SIESTA - Bandung, West Java

Mar 2021 - Mar 2022

- An IT consultant company with education-financial products for Islamic School and University to enable seamless payment and education
- Collaborate with 6 engineers and 2 designers to build a school and university management system using NextJS and Remix

# Web Developer | Nanas Media - Surabaya, East Java

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- A digital enabler to help businesses manage digital marketing with multimedia creative content, programmatic ads and a website to engage with customers
- Collaborate with 5 engineers and a designer to build a canva-like web application using Vue.js
- Use mocha and chai to create an automated testing

#### **Education**

### Bachelor Degree in Computer Information System | Surabaya University - Surabaya, East Java

**Aug 2016** 

- Build a library management system as a final project using Flask and a css library component to recommend popular book genres to librarian
- Build LINE chatbot using PHP as a summer project to help student check their course enrollment status through chatting
- Collaborate with 3 students to work on a freelance project offered by a lecturer to promote a brand new unit opening in the university, built using Laravel and Flutter

### **Projects**

### Covid-19 Indonesia Hub | Personal - https://covid19hub.vercel.app/

Mar 2020

- Bring awareness about the spreading of Covid-19 in Indonesia, was inspired by the Tokyo Metropolitan Covid Dashboard.
- Data scrapped daily from Indonesian government and local news website using NodeJS scrapper
- Frontend is using Vue.js, and the backend is using Vercel's serverless API.

### **Skills**

React.js | Next.js | Vue.js | Nuxt.js | Astro.js | Tailwind